Guide to the Reference Department, Yale University Library, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Reference Department, Yale University Library, records
1930-1985
RU 740
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
8.05
(8 boxes)
The records consist of reports, correspondence, policies, proposals, schedules, stack maps, and minutes documenting the operations of the Yale University Library Reference Department
Yale University. Library
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 32-C (YRG 32-C), Records of Yale University Library departments and offices.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is partially restricted. See inventory for details.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of reports, correspondence, policies, proposals, schedules, stack maps, and minutes documenting the operations of the Yale University Library Reference Department.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Academic libraries -- Reference services; Public services (Libraries); Reference services (Libraries); Yale University. Library
- Records, 1953-1985; Accession 1987-A-056
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2021.
  - ALA American Library Association (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - CRL - Center for Research Libraries (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Connecticut Library Association (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Federation of University Employees - Local 34 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Library of Congress (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - National Union Catalog (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - NELINET - New England Library Information Network (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - New Haven Public Library (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Newsbank, Inc. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - OCLC (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Organization of American Historians (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Reference Dept.
    - Bibliography Reading Room (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Book Selection (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Catalogue Reference (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Collections (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Crawford Collection (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Equipment (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Evacuation Plan and Fire Safety (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - CFCC (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Flex-time (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Government Documents (Box 1, Folder 22 - 23)
    - Index Collection (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Information Desk (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Instruction/Orientation (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Interlibrary Loan
      - Charges (Box 1, Folder 27)
      - CTUW (Box 1, Folder 28)
      - OCLU (Box 1, Folder 29)
      - Reciprocal Agreement (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Keys (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - L and B (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Main Reading Room (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Main Reading Room - Reclassification (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Manual (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Map Collection (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Microtext Room, 1975 March - 1983 November (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Microtext Room, 1956-1974 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Newspapers, 1978 January - 1982 February (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Newspapers, 1953 December - 1972 December (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Periodical Room, 1969-1972 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Periodical Room, 1974-1983 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Office Space (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Persome1 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Personnel Reclassification (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Personnel/Student Assistants (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Policies (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Proposals (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Public reaction (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Staffing, 1974-1983 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Statistics (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Supply and Equipment Orders (Box 2, Folder 52 - 53)
    - Visitors (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Subj. Bibliography (Box 2, Folder 55 - 56)
    - Vertical File Collection (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Research Libraries Group Account (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - RLG
    - Africana (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - Art and Architecture (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Art and Architecture - Task Force (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - Bibliography General (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - BIBPAC (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - Operations, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Reference Dept.
    - Staffing Development, 1975-1980 (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - Schedules (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - Schedules/Weekends (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - Reference desks (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - Publications Office (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - Publications, 1976-1983 (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - RLG - Collection Development Committee (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - RLG - Coordinators (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Research Libraries Group - E. European Special Interest Group (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - RLG - Executive Committee (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - RLG/RSC
    - General (Box 2, Folder 75)
    - Minutes (Box 2, Folder 76)
    - Master Copies (Box 2, Folder 77)
    - On-Site-Access (Box 3, Folder 78)
    - Photography (Box 3, Folder 79)
    - Publicity (Box 3, Folder 80)
    - Sharp Resources Program (Box 3, Folder 81 - 82)
    - Serials (Box 3, Folder 83)
  - RLIN (Box 3, Folder 84 - 85)
  - RLIN II (Box 3, Folder 86)
  - RLG - General (Box 3, Folder 87 - 88)
  - RLG - Government Document Discussion Group (Box 3, Folder 89)
  - Research Libraries Group - Government Documents Special Interest Group (Box 3, Folder 90)
  - RLG/Latin America American Special Interest Group (Box 3, Folder 91)
  - RLG - Law Library (Box 3, Folder 92)
  - Research Libraries Group - Map Special Interest Group (Box 3, Folder 93)
  - RLG
    - Medical Libraries (Box 3, Folder 94)
    - Mid-Eastern Special Interest Group (Box 3, Folder 95)
    - Newsletters (Box 3, Folder 96)
    - Preservation Committee (Box 3, Folder 97)
    - Publicity (Box 3, Folder 98)
    - Public Services Committee (Box 3, Folder 99)
    - Serials Task Force, 1974-1979 (Box 3, Folder 100)
    - Serials Task Force Manual (Box 3, Folder 101)
  - Serials Task Force Progress Reports, 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 102)
  - Research Libraries Group Verif. Svc. (Box 3, Folder 103)
  - RLG - Systems and Techn. App. Committee (Box 3, Folder 104)
  - Reference Dept. - Publications, 1970-1973 (Box 3, Folder 105)
  - Yale University Library/Personnel Hourly Employees (Box 4, Folder 106)
  - Yale Univ. Lib. - Personnel/Orientations (Box 4, Folder 107)
  - Yale Univ. Lib. - Personnel/Reclassification (Box 4, Folder 108)
  - YUL
    - Personnel/Summer Employment (Box 4, Folder 109)
    - Personnel/Women (Box 4, Folder 110)
    - Photo Services (Box 4, Folder 111)
    - Preservation (Box 4, Folder 112)
    - Privileges (Box 4, Folder 113)
    - Professional Staff Association (Box 4, Folder 114)
    - Public Catalog (Box 4, Folder 115)
    - Public Services (Box 4, Folder 116)
    - Reprint Publishers (Box 4, Folder 117)
    - Research Publishers (Box 4, Folder 118)
    - Library Schedules (Box 4, Folder 119)
    - Security (Box 4, Folder 120)
    - Seeley Mudd (Box 4, Folder 121)
    - Social Science (Box 4, Folder 122)
    - Staff Development (Box 4, Folder 123)
    - Publications Committee (Box 4, Folder 124)
    - Orientation (Box 4, Folder 125)
    - Personnel, 1966-1970 (Box 4, Folder 126)
    - Personnel, 1971-1983 (Box 4, Folder 127)
    - SML - Space (Box 4, Folder 128)
    - Storage (Box 4, Folder 129)
    - Summer Term (Box 4, Folder 130)
    - Tech. Services
      - 1972-1981 (Box 4, Folder 131)
      - Automation Counsel (Box 4, Folder 132)
      - Bibliography Department (Box 4, Folder 133)
      - Catalog Dept. (Box 4, Folder 134)
      - Classification (Box 4, Folder 135)
      - I.P.L. (Box 4, Folder 136)
      - Pl-480 (Box 4, Folder 137)
      - Serials, 1973-1979 (Box 4, Folder 138)
      - Serials, 1970-1973 (Box 4, Folder 139)
    - Systems Off (Box 4, Folder 140)
    - Translation (Box 4, Folder 141)
    - User Studies (Box 4, Folder 142)
    - Wing Project (Box 4, Folder 143)
    - Zeta (Box 4, Folder 144)
  - Correspondence, 1980-1983 (Box 4, Folder 145 - 146)
  - Correspondence, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 147)
- Yale University Library. Sterling Memorial Library stack maps, 1983; Accession 2003-A-133
  The materials are open for research.
  - Yale University Library. Sterling Memorial Library stack maps, 1983 (Box 1)
- Card indices describing objects, collections, and funds, of the Yale University Library, circa 1930s-1970s; Accession 2006-A-195 (Box 1–3)
  Scope and Contents
  No inventory available.